Finding Aid for the C. F. Peters Collection of Morton Feldman Manuscripts, 1961-1969
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Compositions by Morton Feldman, 1961-1969, I.; Items 1-79
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Piano (three hands) c1962., 1 ms. score (2 leaves); 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 49)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. At end of score: 12/1/57. At head of title: To Lulla. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corp., 373 Park Ave. So., N.Y. 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6943 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Pieces, violin, piano Piece for violin and piano c1962., 1 ms. score (2 leaves); 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 50)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. At end of score: 12.17.50. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6944 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Projection, no. 1 Projection 1: for solo cello c1962., 4 ms. leaves of music; 17 x 28 cm. (Box 1, Item 51)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Graphic notation. Includes instructions for performance. At end of score: 1950. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y." Assigned publisher's number P6945 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Piano four hands c1962., 1 ms. leaf of music; 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 52)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. At end of score: 4.10.58. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corp., 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6946 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Piano four hands c1962., 2 ms. leaves of music; 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 53)
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 For Franz Kline c1962., 1 ms. score (4 leaves); 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 54)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. Vocalise for soprano, with horn, piano, chimes, violin, and violoncello. At end of score: May 26, 1962. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6948 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 The O'Hara songs c1962., 1 ms. score (8 leaves); 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 55)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. For baritone voice, violin, and violoncello; words by Frank O'Hara. At end of score: 12/62. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corp., 373 Park Ave. So., N.Y. 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6949 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Pieces, piano (1963) Piano piece (to Philip Guston) c1963., 2 ms. leaves of music; 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 56)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. At end of score: 3.3.63. "Copyright 1963 by C.F. Peters Corp., 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6950 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 De Kooning: 1963 c1963., 1 ms. score (7 leaves); 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 57)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. For horn, percussion, piano, violin, and violoncello. Score prepared for reproduction by publisher Peters, with ms. annotations concerning reduction ratio for printing; leaf 1 mounted on cardboard backing. Includes typescript performance instructions (1 leaf; 28 cm.). "Copyright 1963 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York, N.Y."--Label pasted on bottom of leaf 1. "Edition Peters 6951"--Label pasted on bottom of leaf 1.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Vertical thoughts, no. 1 Vertical thoughts 1: for two pianos c1963., 1 ms. score (2 leaves); 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 58)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. At end of score: 4.9.63. Includes typescript performance instructions (1 leaf; 28 cm.), with additional copy in reverse print. "Copyright 1963 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6952 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Vertical thoughts, no. 2 Vertical thoughts 2: for violin and piano c1963., 1 ms. score (2 leaves); 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 59)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. At end of score: 4.25.63. Includes typescript performance instructions (1 leaf; 28 cm.). "Copyright 1963 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6953 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Vertical thoughts, no. 3 Vertical thoughts 3 c1963., 1 ms. score (4 leaves); 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 60)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). For soprano, flute, horn, trumpet, trombone, tuba, piano, celesta, percussion, violin, violoncello, and double bass; words by the composer. Caption title. At end of score: 6/63. Includes typescript performance instructions (1 leaf; 28 cm.). "Copyright 1963 by C.F. Peters Corp., 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6954 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Vertical thoughts, no. 4 Vertical thoughts 4: for piano c1963., 1 ms. leaf of music; 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 61)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. At end of score: 7/7/63. "Copyright 1963 by C.F. Peters Corp., 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6955 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Vertical thoughts, no. 5 Vertical thoughts 5 c1963., 1 ms. score (3 leaves); 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 62)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). For soprano, violin, tuba, percussion, celeste. Caption title. Text: Life is a passing shadow, by the composer. At end of score: 8/12/63. "Copyright 1963 by C.F. Peters Corp., 373 Park Ave. So., N.Y. 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6956 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Rabbi Akiba c1963., 1 ms. score (14 leaves); 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 63)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. For soprano, flute, English horn, trumpet, trombone, tuba, percussion, celesta, violoncello, and double bass; without words. At end of score: Nov. 1963. Includes typescript performance instructions (1 leaf; 28 cm.), with pencil X through the text. "Copyright 1963 by C.F. Peters Corp., 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6957 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Chorus and instruments, no. 1 Chorus and instruments c1963., 1 ms. score (15 leaves); 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 64)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). For chorus (SATB), horn, percussion (1 performer), celesta, violin, violoncello, and double bass; no words or syllables indicated. Caption title. At end of score: Nov. 1963. Includes typescript performance instructions (1 leaf; 28 cm.). "Copyright 1963 by C.F. Peters Corp., 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y. "--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6958 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Christian Wolff in Cambridge: 1963 c1963., 1 ms. score (1 leaf); 38 cm. (Box 1, Item 65)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. For chorus, mixed voices, without text or syllables. Score prepared for reproduction by publisher Peters, with ms. annotations concerning reduction ratio for printing; leaf 1 mounted on cardboard backing. "Copyright 1963 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. South, New York, N.Y."--Label pasted on bottom of leaf 1. "Edition Peters 6959"--Label pasted on bottom of leaf 1.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Christian Wolff in Cambridge c1963., 1 ms. score (1 leaf); 34 cm. (Box 1, Item 66)
    Holograph (Ozalid copy). Caption title. For chorus, mixed voices, without text or syllables. At end of score: 12/19/63. "Copyright 1963 by C.F. Peters Corp., 373 Park Ave. South, New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6959 by Peter's upon publication.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Intersection, no. 4 Intersection 4 c1964., 3 ms. leaves of music; 18 x 28 cm. (Box 1, Item 67)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. For violoncello. Graphic notation. At end of score: Nov. 22, 1953. Includes typescript performance instructions (1 leaf; 18 x 22 cm.). "Copyright 1964 by C.F. Peters Corp., 373 Park Ave. So., N.Y. 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6960 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Projection, no. 3 Projection 3 c1964., 1 ms. score (3 leaves); 18 x 28 cm. (Box 1, Item 68)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. For 2 pianos. Graphic notation. At end of score: Jan. 5, 1951. Includes typescript performance instructions (1 leaf; 17 x 22 cm.). "Copyright 1964 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., N.Y. 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6961 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Projection, no. 5 Projection 5 c1964., 1 ms. score (4 leaves); 18 x 27 cm. (Box 1, Item 69)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. For 3 flutes, trumpet, 3 violoncellos, and 2 pianos. Graphic notation. At end of score: 1951. Includes typescript performance instructions (1 leaf; 18 x 22 cm.). "Copyright 1964 by C.F. Peters Corp., 373 Park Ave. So., N.Y. 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6962 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Numbers c1965., 1 ms. score (8 leaves); 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 70)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. For flute, horn, trombone, tuba, percussion, piano, celesta, violin, violoncello, and double bass. At end of score: Dec. 10, 1964. Includes typescript performance instructions (1 leaf; 28 cm.). "Copyright 1965 by C.F. Peters Corp., 373 Park Ave. So., N.Y. 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6964 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Pieces, piano (1964) Piano piece (1964) c1965., 2 ms. leaves of music; 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 71)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. "Copyright 1965 by C.F. Peters Corp., 373 Park Ave. So., N.Y. 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6965 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Four instruments: violin, cello, chimes and piano c1965., 1 ms. score (6 leaves); 30-32 cm. (Box 1, Item 72)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). At end of score: May 12, 1965. Includes typescript performance instructions on t.p. "Copyright 1965 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. South, New York, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6966 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Pieces, pianos (3) Two pieces for three pianos c1966., 1 ms. score (5 leaves); 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 73)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. At end of piece 1: 12/65; at end of piece 2: 6/66. "Copyright 1966 by C.F. Peters Corp., 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6967 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Chorus and instruments, no. 2 Chorus and instruments II: 1967 c1967., 1 ms. score (2 leaves); 39 cm. (Box 1, Item 74)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. For mixed chorus (SATB), chimes, and tuba. "The chorus sings a consistent open hum throughout on the vowel 'u'" Score prepared for reproduction by publisher Peters, with ms. annotations concerning reduction ratio for printing; leaves 1-2 mounted on cardboard backing. At head of title: "Dedicated to the Brandeis University Choral Union, Alvin Lucier, director." "Copyright 1967 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. South, New York, N.Y."--Label pasted on bottom of leaf 1. "Edition Peters 6968"--Label pasted on bottom of leaf 1.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 First principles c1967., 1 ms. score (17 leaves); 38 cm. (Box 1, Item 75)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. For 2 violins, 3 violoncellos, 2 contrabasses, 2 flute, 2 tubas, trombone, horn, harp, 4 pianos, 2 percussions. At end of score: 1966/1967 (Oct.). Includes typescript performance instructions (1 leaf; 28 cm.) inside wrapper marked "Old, do not use." "Copyright 1967 by C.F. Peters Corp., 373 Park Ave. So., N.Y. 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6969 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 First principles c1967., 7 ms. parts; 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 76)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum masters). Caption title. For 2 violins, 3 violoncellos, 2 contrabasses, 2 flute, 2 tubas, trombone, horn, harp, 4 pianos, 2 percussions. Parts are condensed scores for instrumental groups: movement one has three groups, movement 2 has four groups. Includes two typescript copies of performance instructions (1 leaf ea.; 28 cm.). "Copyright 1967 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. South, N.Y. 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6969 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 False relationships and the extended ending: cello, violin, trombone, 3 pianos, chimes c1968., 1 ms. score (15 leaves); 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 77)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Includes typescript performance instructions on t.p. (1 leaf; 28 cm.). "Copyright 1968 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. South, New York, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6970 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 False relationships and the extended ending: cello, violin, trombone, 3 pianos, chimes c1968., 2 ms. parts; 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 78)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum masters). Caption title. Parts are condensed scores for instrumental groups: Group 1: violin, trombone, piano; Group 2: cello, 2 pianos, chimes. Includes typescript performance instructions (1 leaf; 28 cm.) attached to each parts group. "Copyright 1968 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. South, New York, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6970a upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Between categories: piano, chimes, violin, violoncello (2 of each instrument) c1969., 1 ms. score (9 leaves); 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 79)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Includes instructions for performance on t.p. At end of score: Feb. 9, 1969. "Copyright 1969 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. South, New York, N.Y. "--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6971 upon publication by Peters.
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Contributors
C. F. Peters Corporation
Subjects
Music--Scores and parts; Music--Manuscripts; Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987--Manuscripts
Genres
Scores
Associated Material
Additional Guides
All scores in the collection are cataloged in WorldCat and are available in BISON, the online catalog for the University at Buffalo Libraries, by performing a "Title begins with" search under "C F Peters collection of morton feldman manuscripts".
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Morton Feldman Papers, 1950-1999
Mus. Arc. 2.1
Predominantly secondary materials, including eight boxes of programs and clippings, two boxes of Feldman's published writings, and another box of writings for or about Feldman. Other than a small number of musical fragments, it contains none of Feldman's scores, printed or manuscript.
Morton Feldman Images by Jan Williams, 1974-1979
Mus. Arc. 2.3
A digitized collection of 56 images of Feldman taken by percussionist Jan Williams during European concert tours in 1974, 1977, and 1979.